A Guide to the O. Henry Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6333-a
O. Henry Collection
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6333-a
25 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [17 Dec 1963] 22 Feb 1966
Item Listing
- Manuscript
  - Fragment of an unidentified play, n. d.; AMs, 2 p.
    [Pages 10 and 11 of a play; included dialogue between Bunker and Sailor; Bunker: "I am. Besides that I'm a song and dance artist,. ." Bunker tells the sailor of his various performing skills and displays some magic.]
- Letters
  - S. S. McClure Co. to O. Henry, 1897 Dec 2; AMs, 1 p.
    [Discusses the acceptance of "The Miracle of Lava Canon" and the rejection of other stories.]
  - O. Henry, New York, to [Richard Harding] Davis, [1903] Aug 22; ALS, 3 p.
    [Discusses in detail a brief reference in Davis'
    Three Gringoes in Venezuela and Central America
    as the basis for O. Henry's "
    The Phonograph and the Graft
    . "]
  - [William Aspenwall] Bradley, McClure, Phillips & Co., New York to O. Henry, The Caledonia, New York, 1907 May 14; TLS, 1 p.
    [Discusses an advance, with book-rights as security.]
  - O. Henry, Good Ground, Long Island, to Charles Belmont Davis, Collier's, 1908 Jul 10; ALS, 3 p.
    [Discusses need for an extension of the deadline for a story.]
  - O. Henry, Long Island, to "Colonel" William Griffith, Broadway Magazine, [1908] Jul 10; ALS, 3 p.
    [Mentions a woman visiting soon; discusses being ill,
    Broadway Magazine
    , and a forthcoming story showing some better work.]
  - O. Henry, The Caledonia, to Charles Belmont Davis, [1909] Apr 26; ALS, 2 p.
    [Mentions poor health limiting his work; discusses beginning the "southern series."]
  - O. Henry, The Caledonia, New York, to Charles Belmont Davis at Collier's, [?1908 or 1909]Monday; ALS, 3 p.
    [Discusses and advance in exchange for a promise of 2 or 3 stories.]
  - O. Henry to [Charles Belmont] Davis, [?1908 or 1909] Monday; ALS, 2 p.
    [Discusses an overdue story, a portion of which is enclosed.]
  - O. Henry to [Charles Belmont] Davis], [?1908 or 1909] Wednesday; ALS, 1 p.
    [Mentions the expected completion date of a story.]
  - O. Henry to [Charles Belmont] Davis, [?1908 or 1909] Friday; ALS, 1 p.
    [Mentions illness, the expected completion date of a story.]
  - O. Henry, The Caledonia, New York, to Charles [Belmont] Davis, [?1908 or 1909] Friday; ALS, 3 p.
    [Discusses a long overdue story; mentions sleeplessness.]
  - Sara [Lindsay] Coleman Porter to [John O'Hara] Cosgrove, [1910 Jun]; ALS, 4 p.
    [Discusses the thanks she owes for "unfailing goodness" to O. Henry; mentions O. Henry's debt, in particular to
    Everybody's Magazine
    mentions O. Henry's death; mentions Paris, [George Crouse] Tyler, a play, New York, [Gilman] Hall, Henry James Forman, [Charles Russell] Hancock. ]
  - [John O'Hara Cosgrave] to [Sara Lindsay Coleman Porter, 1910 Jun 14; TL, 3 p. (carbon)
    [Discusses O. Henry's death; mentions the importance of saving O. Henry's letters; mentions [Gilman] Hall, [Charles Russell] Hancock, New York, [George Barr] Baker,
    , [Margaret Worth Porter. ]
  - Sara [Lindsay] Coleman Porter to [John O'Hara] Cosgrave, [1910]; ALS, 7 p.
    [Discusses in detail O. Henry's death and how she might have prevented it; discusses briefly an enclosed snapshot of O. Henry; mentions Margaret [Worth] Porter, [Gilman] Hall, Mrs. [Gilman] Hall. ]
  - O. Henry to "Colonel" [William Griffith], n. d.; ALS, 2 p.
    [Discusses briefly illness preventing his going somewhere.]
  - O. Henry to H. H., n. d.; ALS, 2 p.
    [Discusses briefly a delayed check, work on "past due stuff," a request to make no engagements for him.]
- Photographs
  - Newspaper photograph, n. d.; Photograph
    [From
    The New YorkTimes Book Review
    , 1941 Jan 5; shows O. Henry with arms crossed.]
- Miscellaneous
  - Wedding Invitations, [1907] Nov 27; Invitations w/env
    [Signed by O. Henry with figures in pencil and ink on outside of envelope; two invitations to the wedding of Sara Lindsay Coleman and William Sydney Porter; envelope addresses to Fagg Mallay. ]
  - O. Henry to Charles [Belmont] Davis at Collier's Weekly, 1908 Feb 3; Telegram
    [Discusses pending story.]
  - O. Henry to [Charles Belmont] Davis at Collier's, New York, 1908 Mar [10]; Telegram
    [Discusses a story delayed by illness.]
  - O. Henry to Collier's Weekly, 1909 Jan 6; TDS, 1 p.
    [Discusses contract for five "southern stories" in consideration of a $500 advance; mentions [Charles Belmont] Davis. ]
  - Doubleday, Page & Co., New York to O. Henry, 1909 Feb 1; Ds, 7 p. w/env
    [6 reports of sales of O. Henry's books; 1 account statement incorporating the above.]
  - Newspaper Clipping from The New York Times, 1945 Apr 21; Clipping
    [Reviews
    Best Stories of O. Henry
    , selected by Bennett Cerf and Van H. Cartmell; includes biographical sketch of O. Henry and photograph.]
  - Doubleday, Page & Co. advertisement, n. d.; Printed Flyer
    [Advertises the works of O. Henry; includes a poem " O. Henry" by James Whitcomb Riley and a photograph.]